### Laura Vorgity 9 E Ridge Circle Holland, PA 19053 C: 215-806-2529

arualcurly@aol.com

# Described by parents and fellow teachers as:

Professional~Personable~Organized~Team-Player~Dedicated~Motivated

A child advocate with 13 years' experience focusing on tailoring environment and instruction to the individual needs of all students. Possessing excellent interpersonal communication skills utilized to facilitate a positive rapport with all members of the school community.

# **Professional Experience:**

Alpha House Preschool and Kindergarten at Holy Family University

2005-Present

- Planning and implementing lessons tailored to a variety of learning styles and developmental levels
- Developing a positive rapport with the students, while creating a classroom environment that promotes and supports positive social interaction and active learning
- Utilizing a variety of assessments to evaluate students' individual strengths and needs for more effective curriculum planning
- Creating learning centers for hands-on exploration using an integrated theme-based curriculum
- Supervising and mentoring education majors during their coursework at Holy Family University, providing professional feedback as indicated
- Developed curriculum guide and progress reports
- Supervising after school program for elementary aged students
- Working collaboratively with team teachers and faculty to promote a community of life-long learners
- Modeled and consulted teachers on modifications, accommodations and behavior management strategies with a focus on learners with Autism
- Established Reading Enrichment Summer Program

School District of Upper Moreland Township- Willow Grove, PA

Summer 2012

Extended school year reading teacher (ESY) for special education summer program

- Collected data and provided appropriate lesson plans and activities accordingly
- Used the Individualized Education Program as a guide to select appropriate instructional materials to achieve the goals and objectives specified for each student
- Planned with other teachers during designated meetings

Federation Daycare Services- Lassin Early Learning Center, Philadelphia, PA

Camp Counselor/Substitute Teacher

Summers of 2002 and 2003

- Worked with ages ranging from 6 months to 8 years
- Organized numerous activities to nurture multicultural appreciation

- Participated in educational field trips
- Instructed lessons for individual, small group and whole class
- Established positive relationships with students, parents, fellow teachers and staff

Bensalem Parks and Recreation, Bensalem, PA

Summers of 1998-2000

#### Camp Counselor

- Planned activities for children between the ages of 11 and 13 years
- Served as a role model for the children by promoting positive self-esteem and positive behavior management techniques

### **Education:**

Holy Family University-Pennsylvania 2012-present Continuing education to obtain autism endorsement

Holy Family University-Pennsylvania Master of Education, December 2011 GPA- 4.0

East Stroudsburg University-Pennsylvania Bachelor of Science in Education, December 2004 Major GPA- 3.85

## **Certifications:**

Pennsylvania Instructional II, Early Childhood Education (N-3)

Reading Specialist (K-12)

Special Education (N-12)

### **Community Service:**

- Member of Alpha Omicron Pi Sorority- Social Chair, Vice President of Education and Panhell Delegate
- Participated in various philanthropic activities including those benefitting arthritis research, as well as Special Olympics and March of Dimes
- Recipient of Greek Academic Excellence Award

### **References:**

Available upon request